1999 年 12 月 31 日
宇宙
Space,
看似无边无际
it seems to go on and on forever.
但走到最后
But then you get to the end,
总有一只大猩猩朝你扔水桶
and a gorilla start to throw barrels at you.
游戏结束
这游戏就是这么打的
That's how you play the game.
你太菜了 渣渣
You stink, loser.
喂 弗莱 送披萨了
Hey! Fry, Pizza going out.
赶紧的
Come on!
不要给小费
米切尔 宝贝 你去哪儿
Michelle! Baby! Where you going?
咱俩没戏了 弗莱
It's not working out, Fry.
我把你的东西扔在走廊了
I put your stuff out on the sidewalk!
我讨厌我的生活
I hate my life. I hate my life.
新年快乐
Happy New Year!
低温冷冻技术
自1997年
从未断电
你好 你的外卖…
Hello? Pizza delivery for. . .
"冷·冻·香肠" 先生
"I. C. Wiener. "
噢 该死
Oh, crud!
我还以为在这个年纪
I always thought by this point of my life,
应该是我给别人打恶作剧电话才对
I'd be the one making my crank calls.
敬又一个差劲的千禧年
Here's to another lousy millennium.
1000 年
搞什么…
What the--?
02 秒
01 秒
00 秒
天哪 这里是未来
My God. It's the future.
我的父母 我的同事 我的女朋友
My parents, my co-workers, my girlfriend.
我再也见不到他们了
I'll never see any of them again.
好哎
Yahoo!
飞出个未来
彩色的哟
3000年的船长
Space Pilot 3000
欢迎来到明日世界
Welcome to the world of tomorrow!
你为什么每次都要这样说话
Why do you always have say it that way?
你没听说过什么叫演技吗
Haven't you ever heard of a little thing called showmanship?
来吧 你的命运在等待你
Come, your destiny awaits!
命运分配部
祝你前途顺利
Have a nice future.
酷 就像《星际迷航》一样
Cool, just like in Star Trek. Ow!
下午好 先生
Good afternoon, sir.
名字
Name?
弗莱
Fry.
我是丽拉
I'm Leela.
马上就要过年了
It's New Year's Eve. . .
所以我只想尽快安排好你的命运 早点回家
so I'd like to decide your fate quickly and get out of here.
我能问个问题吗
Can I ask you a question?
只要不是关于我的眼睛
as long as it's not about my eye.
是关于我的眼睛吗
Is it about my eye?
是的吧
Sort of.
问你的吧
Just ask the question.
你的眼睛是怎么回事
What's with the eye?
我是个外星人 行了吧 现在换个话题吧
I'm an alien, all right? Let's drop the subject.
酷啊 外星人
Cool! An alien!
你们占领了地球吗
Has your race taken over the Earth?
不是 我只是在这里工作
No, I just work here.
等一下 那艘飞艇的时间准确吗
Wait a minute. Is that blimp accurate?
是的 现在是2999年12月31日
Yep. It's December 31 st, 2999.
天哪 一千年了
My God! A million years!
你一定觉得挺难过的吧
I'm sure this must be upsetting for you.
怎么说呢 应该是吧 但是
You know, I guess it should be, but...
实际上 我很高兴
actually, I'm glad.
过去已经没有什么值得我留恋的了
I had nothing to live for in my old life.
我破产了 我有份很丢人的工作
I was broke, I had a humiliating job. . .
还有好像我的女朋友也劈腿了
and I'm beginning to suspect my girlfriend might be cheating on me.
至少 在这里你会受到应有的尊重
Well at least here you'll be treated with dignity.
现在 把衣服脱光躺到操作台上去
Now strip naked and get on the probulator.
有意思 你的DNA检测表明
Interesting. Your DNA test shows
你还有一位活着的亲戚
one living relative.
他是你的曾曾曾…曾曾曾侄子
He's your great-great-great...great-great-nephew.
太好了 这个小家伙叫什么名字
That's great! What's the little guy's name?
休伯特·法斯沃斯教授
Professor Hubert Farnsworth.
你知道吗 我是整个未来最幸运的人
You know, I'm the luckiest guy in the whole future.
我获得了新生
I've been given a second chance,
而这次 我不会再做一个失败者
and this time I am not gonna be a total loser.
那是什么
What's that?
你的永久性职业安排
Your permanent career assignment.
送货员
Delivery boy?
不 不要再这样
No! Not again!
随便换一个都好
Please! Anything else.
把你的手拿开
Take your hands off me!
每个人获得的工作都是他们最擅长的
You've been assigned the job you're best at, just like everyone else.
如果我拒绝呢
What if I refuse?
你会被开…
You're fired.
随便
Fine.
…开炮发射到太阳里去
Out of a cannon into the sun.
但是我不喜欢做送货员
But I don't like being a delivery boy!
那没办法
Well that's tough.
很多人都不喜欢自己的工作
lots of people don't like their jobs,
但还是得继续工作
but we do them anyway.
人各有职 身不由己
You gotta do what you gotta do.
伸出手来
Now, hold out your hand.
我要给你植入职业芯片
I'm gonna implant your career chip.
它会将你永久标记为送货员
It'll permanently label you as a delivery boy.
把那个东西拿远点
Keep that away from me!
站好别动 该死
Hold still ! Damn it.
我的眼睛分不清远近
I don't have good depth perception.
给你五秒钟时间放我出来
You've got till I count to five to let me out of here.
一
One
一千年后再见
See you in a thousand years.
噢
Oh!
1000 年
5 分钟
你欠我一次
You owe me one.
哇哦
Whoa!
无线电城变异馆
Radio City Mutant Hall.
酷
Cool!
城际快车
Cross-town express?
外地人
Tourist.
电话亭 我可以打电话给侄子
A phone booth. I can call my nephew.
哇哦 一个货真价实的机器人
Whoa! A real live robot.
不然就是某种劣质的新年装扮
Or is that some kind of cheesy New Year's costume?
来咬我闪亮的屁股
Bite my shiny metal ass.
我看着一点都不亮
It doesn't look shiny to me.
反正比你的亮 肉包子
Shinier than yours, meat bag.
自杀亭
听着 伙计 我有急事
Listen, buddy, I'm in a hurry here.
我们来个双人套餐好了
Let's try for a twofer.
请选择死法
Please select mode of death.
"快速无痛" 还是 "迟缓剧痛"
"Quick and Painless" or "Slow and Horrible. "
我想拨个对方付费的电话
I'd like to place a collect call.
您已选择"迟缓剧痛"
You have selected Slow and Horrible.
有眼光
Good choice!
放马过来吧 宝贝
Bring it on, baby!
快点 快点 赶紧杀了我吧
Come on! Come on! Kill me already!
对了 我叫本德
By the way, my name's Bender.
救命 这是怎么回事
Help! What's happening?
您已经死了 感谢使用"速死速绝"
You are now dead. Thank you for using Stop and Drop.
2008年以来美国最受欢迎的自杀亭
America 's favorite suicide booth since 2008.
没用的破铜烂铁
Lousy, stinking rip-off.
我今天也没有什么别的安排
Well, I didn't have anything else plan for today.
咱们去大醉一场吧
Let's go get drunk!
二、三…嘿
two, three-- Hey!
欢迎来到明日世界
Welcome to the world of tomorrow!
闭嘴 泰瑞
Shut up, Terry.
这事没有商量的余地 丽拉
This is unacceptable, Leela.
你必须找到弗莱并植入芯片
You must find Mr. Fry and install his chip.
听我说 他只是一个无名小卒
Look, he is just a nobody
他就是不想当送货员而已
who doesn't want to be a delivery boy.
我觉得没必要强迫他
I'd really rather not to force it on him.
这是你的工作 不管你喜不喜欢
That's your job, whether you like it or not.
我的工作就是命令你去做你的工作
It's my job to make you do your job,
不管我喜不喜欢
whether I like it or not.
这工作我很喜欢
Which I do! Very much!
现在快干活去
Now get to work.
生活真美好
Life is good.
D R I N K
机器人为什么需要喝酒呢
Why would a robot need to drink?
我才不需要喝酒
I don't need to drink.
我想戒的话随时都可以
I can quit any time I want.
那么它们要逼你做送货员是吗
So they made you a delivery boy?
哥们 那和我的工作一样烂
Man, that's as bad as my job.
真的吗 你是做什么的 本德
Really? What do you do? Bender.
我是一个掰弯机
I'm a bender.
掰弯钢梁 我的程序就是设定来干这个的
I bend girders. That's all what I'm programmed to do.
你很在行吗
You any good at it?
开玩笑 我可是业界明星
You kidding? I was a star.
我能把钢梁掰成任意角度
I could bend a girder to any angle.
三十度 三十二度
30 degrees, 32 degrees.
随便你说
You name it.
三十一度
但是我不想继续活下去了
But I couldn't go on living
自从我发现它们是用来做什么的
once I found out what the girders were for.
做什么的
What?
自杀亭
Suicide booths.
弗莱 很高兴认识你
Fry, it was a pleasure meeting you.
我要自杀去了
I'm gonna kill myself.
等等 你是我唯一的朋友了
Wait! You're the only friend I have.
你真的想和机器人做朋友
You really want a robot for a friend?
是的 从小就想
Yeah, ever since I was six.
好吧
Okay,
但是我不希望别人以为我们是人机恋
but I don't want people thinking we're robosexuals.
所以有人问起的话 就说你是我的调试员
So if anyone asks, you're my debugger.
哦不 是那个独眼龙
Oh, no. It's the cyclops.
别看 别看
Don't look! Don't look!
我没在看
I'm not looking.
警察编号 1B-Dl
This is Officer 1B-Dl,
请求支援
requesting backup.
我们五分钟后赶到
We'll be there in five minutes.
我们可以躲在这里
We can hide in here!
这里星期二免费
It's free on Tuesdays!
欢迎来到人头博物馆
Welcome to the Head Museum.
我是伦纳德·尼莫
I'm Leonard Nimoy.
斯波克
Spock?!
做这个手势
Do the thing.
我已经不能这么做了
I don't do that anymore.
真是难以置信
This is unbelievable!
你们平时都做什么
What do you heads do all day?
我们与人们分享经验和智慧
We share our wisdom with those who seek it.
这是一种体面的生活方式
It's a life of quiet dignity.
喂食时间
Feeding time!
很抱歉 但我必须给你安装芯片
I'm sorry, Fry, but I have to install your career chip.
你既然抱歉 为什么还要做呢
Well, if you are sorry then why are you doing it?
这是我的工作
It's my job.
人各有职 身不由己
You gotta do what you gotta do.
小心点
Watch it!
够了 你上了我的黑名单了
That's it. You just made my list!
停下 淘气包 坏总统
Stop it! Down boy! Bad president!
行了 伙计 离那些头远一点
All right, buddy. Step away from the head.
我要让他尝尝24世纪的厉害
I'm gonna get 24th-century on his ass.
别这样 各位警官
Please, officers!
没有必要动用原力
There's no need to use force.
我们会处理的 怪女士
Let us handle this, weirdy.
行了 他只是一个来自无知年代的可怜虫
Come on. He's just a poor kid from the Stupid Ages.
把你的大鼻子挪开 独眼龙
Keep your big nose out of this, Eyeball.
没有人敢取笑我的鼻子
No one makes fun of my nose.
该死
Damn.
你们刚刚完全失控了
You guys were totally out of control.
那是我们的工作 我们是维和警察
That's our job. We're peace officers.
你也知道规定 "人各有职 身不由己"
You know the law. "You gotta do what you gotta do. "
噢 我们被困住了
Oh! We're trapped!
等一等 你不是掰弯机吗
Wait a second ! You're a bender, right?
只要你掰弯铁栏我们就能逃出去了
We can get out of here if you just bend the bars.
别做梦了 肉包子
Dream on, skin-tube!
我的程序只允许我为建造工作而掰
I'm programmed to bend for constructive purposes.
我看起来像一个逆掰弯机吗
What do I look like? A de-bender?
谁管你的程序是编来干什么的
Who cares what you are programmed for?
如果有人给你编了跳楼的程序 你会照做吗
If someone programmed  you to jump off a bridge, would you do it?
我得检查一下我的程序
I'll have to check my program.
会的
Yep!
开门
Open up!
拜托 本德
Come on, Bender.
自己的生活自己做主
It's up to you to make your own decisions on life.
那就是人和机器人与动物的区别
It separates people and robots from animals. . .
还有机器动物
. . .and animal-robots.
你胡说八道 弗莱
You're full of crap, Fry!
你的话很有说服力 弗莱
You make a persuasive argument, Fry.
加油本德 你能做到的
Come on, Bender! You can do it!
不行 我做不到
Can't. I can't do it!
太好了
Yes!
你是对的
You were right, Fry.
从现在起 我想掰就掰
From now on, I'm going to bend
无论任何东西 任何时间 还是任何人
what I want, when I want, who I want.
没什么能阻止我
I'm unstoppable!
我不知道你是怎么做到的
I don't know how you did that.
等等
Wait!
不了 谢谢
No thanks!
看来我们当中必须有人掰弯这个栅栏
Looks like one of us will have to bend this grate.
噢
Aw!
Fenusians
No home
天哪 这是什么
Good Lord! What is this?
这是旧纽约陷落的遗迹
It's the decaying ruins of old New York.
欢迎回家 伙计
Welcome home, pal.
那是我住过的街区
It's my old neighborhood.
天哪 勾起了我不少回忆
Man, this brings back a lot of memories.
你自己记着好了
Keep them to yourself.
这里就是我和女友第一次约会的地方
This is where I brought my girlfriend on our very first date.
天哪 她已经死了
My God! She's gone.
我认识的 在乎的人全都死了
Everyone I ever knew or cared about is gone.
这儿还有个你认识的人
Wait, there's someone you know.
你就不能放过吗
Can't you leave me alone?
我已经够悲惨的了
I'm miserable enough already.
我知道这不能给你多少慰藉
Look, I know it's not much consolation,
但是我理解你的感受
but I understand how you feel.
你不懂 我无家可归 没有家人
No you don't. I've got no home, no family.
没有朋友
No friends.
我的世界已不复存在
My whole world is gone.
你不可能了解如此孤单是什么感觉
You can't possibly understand what it feels like to be so alone.
我了解
I understand.
我是这个星球上唯一的独眼人
I'm the only one-eyed alien on this whole planet.
我的父母从小就抛弃了我
My parents abandoned me here as a baby.
我甚至不知道它们来自哪个星系
I don't even know what galaxy they were from.
我知道孤单是什么感觉
I know how it feels to be alone.
丽拉 我不了解这个世界
Look Leela, I don't understand this world,
但很明显你了解
but you obviously do.
所以我认命了
So I give up.
如果你真的认为我应该做一个送货员
If you really think I should be a delivery boy,
那我就做吧
I'll do it.
你的芯片
Your chip!
你在做什么
What are you doing?
辞职
Quitting.
为什么
Why?
因为我从始至终都想这么做
Because I've always wanted to.
直到遇到你 我才意识到这一点
I just never realized it until I met you.
你来凑什么热闹
What is the matter with you?
我只是想参与这个特别的时刻
I wanted to be part of the moment.
他偷了我的戒指
Hey! He stole my ring!
抱歉
Sorry.
好的 这下戒指消失之谜解开了
Well, that solves the mystery of the missing ring.
这值得干一杯
This calls for a drink.
我不想破坏气氛
I don't want to spoil the party,
但是现在我们都成了弃业犯
but we're all job-deserters now.
我们没有工作也没地方可去
we are unemployed and nowhere to go.
纠正：我们虽然没有工作
Correction: we are unemployed. . .
但是我们有个老亲戚可以投奔
but we have an old relative to mooch off of.
大家好 我是迪克·克拉克的头
Hello, I'm Dick Clark's head.
欢迎收看3000年特别版
Welcome to a special year 3000 edition of
新年摇滚夜
New Year's Rockin' Eve!
你是谁
Who are you?
我是你亲爱的老舅舅弗莱
I'm your dear old Uncle Fry.
我没有什么弗莱舅舅
I don't have an Uncle Fry.
你现在有了
You do now!
天哪 我真的是你的侄子
By God, I am your nephew!
这真是太不可思议了
This is absolutely incredible!
我们能跟你要点钱吗
Can we have some money?
哦 当然不行
Oh, my, no.
让我带你们参观一下
Let me show you around.
这是我的实验桌
That's my lab table and
这是我的工作椅
this is my work stool.
那边那个是我的跨星际飞船
And over there is my intergalactic spaceship.
还有这些是我收集的各种长度的导线
And here's where I keep assorted lengths of wire.
一艘真正的太空飞船
A real live spaceship!
我自己设计的
I designed it myself.
还是来看看我收集的各种长度的导线吧
Let me show you some of the different lengths of wire I used.
注意了 各位弃业犯
Attention, job-deserters!
举起手走出来
Come out with your hands up!
你们已经被半包围了
We have you partially surrounded!
不
No!
抓住这些混混
Get those bums.
我们完蛋了
We're boned.
我们能用这艘飞船逃走吗
Can't we get away in the ship?
从技术上讲是可行的
I suppose it is technically possible.
但是我都已经穿上睡衣了
Though I am already in my pajamas.
我带大家出去
I'll get us out of here.
有人懂得驾驶吗
Can anyone drive stick?
我能
I can.
只要别让我漂移停船就行
As long as I don't have to parallel park.
如果他们胆敢起飞
If they try to take off,
就打得他们满屁股激光
give them an ass full of laser.
准备升空
Prepare for lift off!
发射
Blast off!
开火 开火
Fire! Fire!
我看不清楚
I can't see nothing.
景色倒是不错
Pretty, though.
好啊
Yeah!
我想 没有了工作
So I guess without jobs
我们得永远逃亡了
we'll be fugitives forever.
那倒未必
Not necessarily.
我想问问你们三个
Are you three, by any chance,
有没有兴趣成为我的新船员呢
interested in becoming my new spaceship crew?
新船员 你的老船员怎么了
New crew? What happened to the old crew?
那些可怜老王八…但是
Those poor sons of-- but
那不重要
That's not important.
重要的是 我需要新船员
What's important is I need a new crew.
有兴趣吗
Anyone interested?
有 有
Yes! Yes!
这正是我梦寐以求的工作
That's exactly the job I've always wanted!
谢谢你提供的职位 教授
Thanks for the offer, professor.
但是我们没有合适的职业芯片
but we don't have the proper career chips.
这不成问题
That won't be a problem.
算你们走运
As luck would have it,
我保留了旧船员的芯片
I saved the chips from my previous crew.
太棒了
This is awesome!
我们是不是要在宇宙中穿梭
Are we gonna flight through space
对抗各种怪物 还有
Fighting monsters and
教会外星女人如何去爱吗
teach alien women to love?
如果你的意思是运输货物的话
If by that you mean transporting cargo,
没错
Then yes.
这是我为了赚点研究经费而发起的小生意
It's a little home business I started to fund my research.
酷 我要做什么工作呢
Cool! What's my job gonna be?
你要负责确保货物
You'd be responsible for ensuring that
安全的抵达目的地
the cargo reaches its destination.
这么说我是一个送货员
So I'm gonna be a delivery boy?
正是
Exactly!
好啊
All right!
我是一个送货员
I'm a delivery boy!